In the example in the quiz, the math says the result should be 1.0.
クイズの例では 計算では 結果が 1.0になるはずですが
But, the code says 0.95.
コードでは 0.95です
That's a big difference.
これは 大きな違いです
Go ahead, replace the one billion with just one, and
ここで 10億を 1に 置き換えたとすると
you'll see that the error becomes very tiny.
誤差は とても小さい値に なります
We're going to want the values involved in the calculation of this
この 大きな損失関数の 計算に 含まれる値を
big lost function that we care about, to never get too big or too small.
大きすぎず 小さすぎない値に したいと 思います
One good guiding principle is that we always want our variables to have 0 mean
目安として 適切なのは 可能な限り 変数の 平均が ゼロ
and equal variance whenever possible.
そして分散が 等分散になるように することです
On top of the numerical issues, there are also a really good
最適化を行う際に 平均を およそゼロにし 分散を
mathematical reasons to keep values you compute roughly around a mean of zero
等分散にすることには 数値的な メリットだけでなく
and equal variance when you're doing optimization.
計算上の理由も あります
A badly conditioned problem means that the optimizer has to do
問題の条件が 悪いと 最適化の際に
a lot of searching to go and find a good solution.
あちこちを 探し回らないと よい解が 見つかりません
A well conditioned problem makes it a lot easier for
問題の条件が よければ
the optimizer to do its job.
最適化の 処理は はるかに 楽になります
If you're dealing with images it's simple.
画像を 扱っている場合は 単純です
You can take the pixel values of your image, they are usually between 0 and
画像の ピクセル値を 取得します 通常は
255.
0～255です
And simply subtract 128 and divide by 128.
128を 引いて 128で 割るだけです
It doesn't change the content of your image, but it makes it much easier for
画像の内容は 変わりませんが 最適化の際の 数値処理が
the optimization to proceed numerically.
はるかに 簡単になります
You also want your weights and biases to be initialized at
また 重みと バイアスを 初期化して
a good enough starting point for the gradient descent to proceed.
勾配降下法を 進めるのに 適した状態にします
There are lots of fancy schemes to find good initialization values.
よい初期値を 見つけるための スキームには 優れたものが たくさんあります
But we're going to focus on a simple general method.
ここでは 単純で 一般的な 方法を 取り上げたいと 思います
Draw the weights randomly from a Gaussian distribution would mean zero and
ガウス分布に従う 重みを ランダムに描きます
standard deviation sigma.
平均はゼロ 標準偏差は σです
The sigma value determines the order of magnitude of your outputs
σの値によって 最適化の
at the initial point of your optimization.
初期点の 指標が 決まります
Because of the softmax on top of it, the order of magnitude also determines
さらに softmaxがあるため 指標により
the peakiness of your initial probability distribution.
初期確率分布の 尖度も決まります
A large sigma will mean that your distribution will have large peaks,
σが大きければ 分布の ピークが 大きくなり
it's going to be very opinionated.
かなり独断的に なります
A small sigma means that your distribution is very uncertain about
σが小さければ 分散は 非常に不確かな
things.
ものになります
It's usually better to begin with an uncertain distribution, and
普通は 不確かな 分散で 始めて
let the optimization become more confident as the training progress.
トレーニングを 進めながら 最適化の 信頼性を 高めるのが 妥当です
So, use a small sigma to begin with.
そのため 最初は 小さいσを 使います
Okay, so
さて これで
now we actually have everything we need to actually train this classifier.
クラシファイ（識別器）の トレーニングに 必要な ものが 揃いました
We've got our training data, which is normalized to have zero mean and
トレーニングデータは 平均 ゼロと
unit variance.
単位分散で 正規化しました
We multiply it by a large matrix, which is initialized with random weights.
それに ランダムな重みで 初期化した 大規模な 行列を かけました
We apply the softmax then the cross-entropy loss and
softmaxと クロスエントロピー損失を 適用し
we calculate the average of this loss over the entire training data.
トレーニングデータ全体の 損失の平均を 求めました
Then our magical optimization package computes
そして 魔法の 最適化パッケージが
the derivative of this loss with respect to the weights in to the biases, and
この損失の微分係数を 重みと バイアスに 関して 計算し
takes a step back in the direction opposite to that derivative.
微分係数とは 逆の方向に 一歩 後退します
And then, we start all over again,
そして また最初から
we repeat the process until we reach minimum of the loss function.
プロセスを 開始し 損失関数が 最小になるまで 繰り返します